Kashyap Tamakuwala

San Jose, California | kashyaptamakuwala@gmail.com | (341)500-3019 | LinkedIN | Github | Portfolio

SUMMARY

A passionate software developer experienced in working with various web technologies along with Machine Learning applications. A quick learner with an ability to create innovative, reliable, and user-friendly systems. An enthusiastic human with strong communication and interpersonal skills.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Skills Javascript, Typescript, Python, R, C, C++, Java,

Web Technologies ReactJs, NodeJs, ExpressJs, Redux, GraphQL, HTML/CSS, Django

Cloud Technologies
Databases
Databases
Docker, Kubernetes, AWS
MySql, Postgresql, MongoDB
Tensorflow, Pytorch, Git

EDUCATION

Master of Science in Artificial Intelligence San Jose State University, California (Aug. 2021 - May. 2023)

Courses: Data Mining, Machine learning, Math for Decision Making, Artificial intelligence

Bachelor of Technology in Computer Engineering Dharmsinh Desai University, Gujarat (Aug. 2017 - May. 2021) Courses: Software Engineering, Advanced Data Structures & Algorithms, DBMS, Computer Networks

WORK EXPERIENCE

Graduate Research Assistant: San Jose State University

(Feb. 2023 - present)

- Researching different ways to encode long documents and perform classification.
- Developing a method to visualize reasoning behind prediction of a model.

Software Development Intern: Stanford Health Care

(Jun. 2022 - Dec. 2022)

- Engineered a concurrent and distributed algorithm using C# and python for mapping web addresses in real-time.
- Managed a variety of micro-services, with help of docker and git, to facilitate transfer of private health data between enterprises.
- Designed reusable react components for a Content Management System.
- Scaled architecture to handle more than 5k requests per second concurrently.

Machine Learning Intern: IIT Bombay

(Jan. 2021 - Apr. 2021)

- Developed IndoWordNet, a web application for searching words in a lexical knowledge base of multilingual wordnets and ontologies stored in Mysql and PostgreSQL Database.
- Researched a Sequence to Sequence model using Pytorch and Tensorflow to extract important data from accident reports.
- Achieved a BLEU(BiLingual Evaluation Understudy) score of 0.6 from formulated model.

ACADEMIC PROJECTS

ShareEdu | 🚺

MEAN Stack, Redux, AWS

- Devised and built an architecture using micro-services in NodeJs for universities to manage online courses.
- Implemented functionalities for note-making, course resource distribution, and video sharing by professors to facilitate easy learning for students.
- Deployed application on an AWS EC2 instance and stored images in an S3 bucket.

UberEats-Clone | 😯

MERN Stack, Redux, AWS, GraphQL

- Designed a scalable MERN Stack application and implemented state management using redux to improve performance.
- Configured Kafka middleware (message broker) to support 10k concurrent users.
- Reduced latency by 8% by using data-pooling in MongoDB to enable multi-threaded connections.

Library Automation | 🕤

Django, JavaScript, SQL, bootstrap

- Collaborated and lead a team of 4 to develop distributed software to automate library systems for efficiently keeping track of transactions.
- Developed backend APIs to support 12+ features such as Adding new books, Due date notification, Late Fees calculation.